Patrick Odida

Results-driven Software Developer with hands-on experience utilizing JavaScript ES6+, ReactJS, TailwindCSS, HTML5, CSS3, Strapi for backend, and version control (Git and GitHub). Adept at problem-solving, collaboration, and creating visually captivating and responsive web interfaces

Kampala,Uganda, (+256 777073440) patrick.o.odida@gmail.com

PROJECTS

KwataBus Web App — Bus Ticketing Web Application

Developed a functional and fully responsive bus ticketing Web Application using modern technologies and tools i.e ReactJS, TailwindCSS, & Strapi for backend.

Relevant Link: A live viewing demo on Netlify KwataBus Web App

Portfolio Website — Personal website for my portfolio projects

Developed a fully responsive portfolio website to showcase my projects and experience in Front-end development.

Relevant Link: A live viewing demo on Netlify Portfolio Website

EXPERIENCE

KwataBus Web App Project, Kampala — Technical Team Lead & PM

MARCH 2024 - JUNE 2024

Led a team to develop KwataBus web app, overseeing project management, code reviews, effective collaboration, and timely milestone delivery.

Skenya Motors U Ltd, Kampala — Service Advisor

MAY 2017 - AUG 2021

Diagnosed and resolved automotive issues through logical troubleshooting resulting in a 50% reduction in repeat jobs and good customer experience.

Nakumatt U Ltd, Kampala — IT Support

SEPT 2015 - APRIL 2017

Installation, troubleshooting, Network configuration, and updating software Apps & Operating systems increasing Point of sale(POS) uptime by over 30%.

EDUCATION

Uganda College of Commerce, Soroti — *Diploma*

JUNE 2011 - JUNE 2013

Business Studies - Accounting.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

Kanzu Code Foundation, Kampala — Certificate

FEB 2024 - JUNE 2024 Front-end Development

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ES6+ TailwindCSS ReactJS Strapi for backend Git and GitHub version control Responsive design

AWARDS

Front-end Best Student Award -Front-end Bootcamp(Kanzu Code Foundation)

LANGUAGES

English